A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, American Literary Manuscripts (ALM) collection FA718
Rockefeller Archive Center
- LINDSEY, Howard, 1955-1961 (Box 6, Folder 136)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 05800294 (58-294), New Dramatists, GRANTS-IN-AID PROGRAM FOR PLAYWRIGHTS; and Project file C-623, Grants in Aid program for the playwright in theater.
- LIPPMAN, Walter, 1955-1959 (Box 6, Folder 137)
- LOWELL, Robert, 1958-1962 (Box 6, Folder 138)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-918, Grants in Aid program for novelists and poets; Grant file 06000132 (60-132), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR POETS AND FICTION WRITERS; Grant file 06090149 (60-149), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), COOPERATION OF THEATERS AND OPERA COMPANIES IN PROGRAM FOR POETS AND FICTION WRITERS.
- LYNES, Russell, 1956-1969 (Box 6, Folder 139)
- LYTLE, Andrew, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 140)
- McCARTHY, Mary, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 141)
- McCULLERS, Carson, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 142)
- MacDONALD, Dwight, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 143)
- MacGOWAN, Kenneth, 1957-1960 (Box 6, Folder 144)
- MacLEISH, Archibald, 1955-1969 (Box 6, Folder 145)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Log file #L64-503, University of the West Indies, Creative Arts Conference; Project file B-953: Support of Publication for University Presses, in the Humanities and Social Sciences; and Project file C-918, Grants in Aid program for novelists and poets.
  MacLeish letter of December 7, 1959 and October 22, 1959 include references to William Lyon Phelps.
- MALAMUD, Bernard, 1958-1965 (Box 6, Folder 146)
- MARSHALL, Paula, 1963-1965 (Box 6, Folder 147)
- MAXWELL, William, 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 148)
- MAYS, Benjamin E., 1957-1967 (Box 6, Folder 149)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 06400415 (64-415), Atlanta University Center, Inc., FACULTY AND STAFF DEVELOPMENT AND STUDENT ASSISTANCE (GENERAL SUPPORT).
- MAYS, James Boyer, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 150)
- MEREDETH, William, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 151)
  Grant file 06000132 (60-132), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR POETS AND FICTION WRITERS.
- MERWIN, W. S., 1958-1965 (Box 6, Folder 152)
- MICHENER, James, 1954-1961 (Box 6, Folder 153)
  Includes documents culled from Log files #L61-480.
- MILLER, Arthur, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 154)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Log file #L58-420, Ford Foundation -Conference on the theater.
- MILLER, Merle, 1960-1963 (Box 7, Folder 155)
- MILLER, Perry, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 156)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 05500164 (55-164), The University Of Delhi, TO SUPPORT A PROFESSORSHIP IN AMERICAN CIVILIZATION AND SOCIAL-POLITICAL INSTITUTIONS.
- MOORE, Marianne, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 157)
- MORRIS, Hilda, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 158)
- MORRIS, Wright, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 159)
- MOSS, Howard, 1958-1963 (Box 7, Folder 160)
- MUMFORD, Lewis, 1960-1971 (Box 7, Folder 161)
- NEMEROV, Howard, 1958-1963 (Box 7, Folder 162)
- NIMS, John Frederick, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 163)
- NIN, Anais, 1963-1966 (Box 7, Folder 164)
- O'CONNOR, Flannery, 1958-1963 (Box 7, Folder 165)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-638, Program for the creative writer; Project file C-918, Grants in Aid program for novelists and poets; and Grant file 05900121 (59-121), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR CREATIVE WRITERS.
- O'HARA, Frank, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 166)
- OLSEN, Tillie, 1958-1958 (Box 7, Folder 167)
- ORLOVITZ, Gil, 1959-1965 (Box 7, Folder 168)
- PATCHEN, Kenneth, 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 169)
- PIAGET, Jean, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 170)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 07950310 (79-310), University Of Geneva, SUPPORT OF THE ACTIVITIES OF THE INTERNATIONAL CENTRE FOR GENETIC EPISTEMOLOGY.
- PORTER, Katherine Anne, 1958-1966 (Box 7, Folder 171)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-638, Program for the creative writer; Project file C-623, Grants in Aid program for the playwright in theater; and Grant file 05900121 (59-121), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR CREATIVE WRITERS
- POWERS, James F., 1959-1966 (Box 7, Folder 172)
- PROKOSCH, Frederick, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 173)
- PURDY, James, 1959-1963 (Box 7, Folder 174)
- PYNCHON, Thomas, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 175)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-918, Grants in Aid program for novelists and poets; and Grant file 06090149 (60-149), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), COOPERATION OF THEATERS AND OPERA COMPANIES IN PROGRAM FOR POETS AND FICTION WRITERS.
- RAGO, Henry, 1958-1970 (Box 7, Folder 176)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 06890194 (68-194), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), TRAVEL AND STUDY AWARDS; Log file #L58-534, “Support for editorial expenses involved in special issues devoted to contemporary Israeli verse; and Log file #L64-918, Poetry Magazine.
- RAHV, Philip, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 177)
- RANSOM, John Crowe, 1958-1961 (Box 7, Folder 178)
- REED, Ishmael, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 179)
- RICE, Elmer, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 180)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-623, Grants in Aid program for the playwright in theater.
- RICH, Adrienne, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 181)
- RODMAN, Sheldon, 1962-1966 (Box 7, Folder 182)
- ROETHKE,Theodore, 1958-1964 (Box 7, Folder 183)
- ROOSEVELT, Anna Eleanor, 1951-1960 (Box 7, Folder 184)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file D-212, Speaker Services for the United States - General program, 1960; and Log file #L59-1182, Mediterrainian Congress for Culture, Support for meeting, October 1960.
- ROSTEN, Leo, 1962-1965 (Box 7, Folder 185)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 06200459 (62-459), Trustees Of Dartmouth College, JAPANESE-AMERICAN ROUND TABLE DISCUSSION OF INTERNATIONAL PROBLEMS.
- ROSTEN, Norman, 1959-1963 (Box 7, Folder 186)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-918, Grants in Aid program for novelists and poets; and Project file C-623, Grants in Aid program for the playwright in theater.
- ROTH, Philip, 1959-1969 (Box 7, Folder 187)
  A. Penn letter of December 21, 1960 contains references to Norman Mailer and Bud Schulberg.
- RUKEYSER, Muriel, 1958-1963 (Box 7, Folder 188)
- SANDBURG, Carl, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 189)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-918, Grants in Aid program for novelists and poets; and Grant file 05900121 (59-121), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR CREATIVE WRITERS.
- SARGEANT, Winthrop, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 190)
- SAROYAN, William, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 191)
- SARTON, Eleanor May, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 192)
  Sarton letter of march 8, 1963 inlcues references to Eva LeGallienne.
- SCHEVILL, James, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 193)
- SCHORER, Mark, 1957-1963 (Box 8, Folder 194)
- SCHUYLER, George, 1958-1970 (Box 8, Folder 195)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Log File #L58-1007, Worldwide Broadcasting Foundation, “Hour-a-day radio program to Africa”.
- SCHWARTZ, Delmore, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 196)
- SCOTT, Winfield Townley, 1958-1959 (Box 8, Folder 197)
- SEXTON, Anne, 1963-1969 (Box 8, Folder 198)
- SHAPIRO, Karl, 1958-1964 (Box 8, Folder 199)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-918, Grants in Aid program for novelists and poets; and Project file C-638, Program for the creative writer.
  Karl Shapiro letters of March 6, 1964 and March 19, 1964 contain references to Wallace Stevens.
- SIMPSON, Louis, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 200)
- SMART, Charles A., 1964 (Box 8, Folder 201)
- SMITH, William Jay, 1963-1966 (Box 8, Folder 202)
- SNODGRASS, W. D., 1960-1965 (Box 8, Folder 203)
- SONTAG, Susan, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 204)
- SORRENTINO, Gilbert, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 205)
- SPENCER, Elizabeth, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 206)
- STALLMAN, Robert, 1958-1963 (Box 8, Folder 207)
  Letter of March 8, 1963 includes references to Charles Eaton.
- STEEGMULLER, Francis, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 208)
- STEELE, Max, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 209)
- STEGNER, Wallace, 1958-1963 (Box 8, Folder 210)
- STEINBECK, John, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 211)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Log file #L58-1016, “Grant to support filming of John Steinbeck’s short play ‘Flight’”.
- STRAND, Mark, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 212)
- STYRON, William, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 213)
- SUMMERS, Hollis, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 214)
- SWADOS, Harvey, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 215)
- SWALLOW, Alan, 1959-1967 (Box 8, Folder 216)
- SWENSON, May, 1963-1965 (Box 8, Folder 217)
- TAYLOR, Peter, 1958-1963 (Box 8, Folder 218)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-638, Program for the creative writer; and Grant file 06000132 (60-132), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR POETS AND FICTION WRITERS.
- THOMSON, Virgil, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 219)
- THURSTON, Jarvis, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 220)
- TRILLING, Lionel, 1953-1970 (Box 8, Folder 221)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Grant file 06200445 (62-445), The International House Of Japan, Inc., JAPANESE-AMERICAN ROUND TABLE DISCUSSION OF INTERNATIONAL PROBLEMS.
- TUCCI, Niccolo, 1958-1961 (Box 8, Folder 222)
- ULLMAN, Victor, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 223)
- UNTERMEYER, Jean, 1959-1963 (Box 8, Folder 224)
- UNTERMEYER, Louis, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 225)
- UPDIKE, John, 1959-1963 (Box 8, Folder 226)
- Van DOREN, Mark, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 227)
- Van ITALLIE, Jean Claude, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 228)
  Includes documents culled from ford Foundation records, Grant file 06900578 (69-578), New York University, EXPERIMENTAL DEVELOPMENT OF NEW DRAMATIC MATERIALS.
- VAZAKAS, Byron, 1958-1963 (Box 8, Folder 229)
- VONNEGUT, Kurt, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 230)
- WAGONER, David, 1963-1965 (Box 8, Folder 231)
- WALSH, Chad, 1960-1966 (Box 8, Folder 232)
- WARD, Mary Jane, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 233)
- WARREN, Robert Penn, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 234)
- WEISS, Theodore, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 235)
- WELTY, Eudora, 1958-1965 (Box 8, Folder 236)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-918, Grants in Aid program for novelists and poets; Project file C-638, Program for the creative writer; and Grant file 06000132 (60-132), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR POETS AND FICTION WRITERS.
- WHEELOCK, John Hall, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 237)
- WILBUR, Richard, 1958-1963 (Box 9, Folder 238)
- WILDER, Thornton, 1958-1963 (Box 9, Folder 239)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-918, Grants in Aid program for novelists and poets; Project file C-623, Grants in Aid program for the playwright in theater; and Log file #L58-420, Ford Foundation -Conference on the theater.
- WILLIAMS, Tennessee, 1959-1962 (Box 9, Folder 240)
- WILLIAMS, William Carlos, 1958-1960 (Box 9, Folder 241)
- WILSON, Edmond, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 242)
- WOLFE, Thomas, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 243)
  Includes documents culled from Ford Foundation records, Project file C-712, Baylor Theatre - Experiment in dramatization, "Of Time and the River" by Thomas Wolfe.
- WOUK, Hermann, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 244)
- YOUNG, Marguerite, 1958-1970 (Box 9, Folder 245)
- ZUKOFSKY, Louis, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 246)
  Includes material on the publisher 'Jargon Books'.
- Central Index cards for ALM collection (Box 9, Folder 247)
  Includes copies of the Ford Foundation's Central Index cards (FA736) for writers considered for the ALM project.
- Lists of writers for ALM collection (Box 9, Folder 248)
- ALM collection finding aid and MARC record, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 249)
  Includes original ALM collection finding aid (circa 1980s), and a MARC record from the Ford Foundation's library catalog (1989).
- ALM project notes, 1972-1977 (Box 9, Folder 250)